

925.785.1106 billp@billpratt.net 14207 N Maple Road, Collinsville, OK, 74021

Profile

I have spent over 20 years working in technology, specializing in Unix systems engineering and software engineering. I am interested in software engineering, professional services, as well management roles. Not only can I speak the language of my colleagues, I also help provide direction and utilize resources to help myself and my team learn and grow. I strive to work in an environment where I am immersed with colleagues I respect and who challenge me. I sit in a unique position in my field as many say I have an amazing engineering mind coupled with the sales ability to work with the business and customers to deliver solutions that truly satisfy everyone involved. These unique talents align me exactly with the needs of all engineering related positions. I really enjoy a challenge, it is truly what keeps me motivated and driven. You may view my Github at http://github.com/williampratt. Unfortunately many repos are private and some under NDA. If you would like further samples I would be happy to provide them.

Specialties: Leading Software Development Teams using a hands-on approach, Splunk, Python, Ruby / Ruby on Rails, Amazon Web Services, GCP, Hadoop, Perl, Web technologies (html, css, javascript, etc), C++, C#, Unix / Linux systems engineering, FortiGate, Juniper, Foundry, Redback, Mysql, Oracle, MSsql, Postgress, too many more to list here.

Experience

SPLUNK CONSULTANT (SCCC CERTIFIED) / R&D LEAD; REMOTE - AUGUST 2020 - CURRENT

Provide Splunk consultant services to top companies, both on-premise and in the cloud. This includes the full scope of the stack, from backend services connections to dashboards and training. My Research and Development Lead role allows me to mentor fellow employees on systems and software development projects while leading in-house development of products.

SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT DR MCNATTY & ASSOCIATES; REMOTE - MAY 2017 - DECEMBER 2019

Full-stack Ruby on Rails and Java developer specializing in integrating applications into a modern environment. I performed extensive work with Oracle BI and Unifier and building tools related to integration, dashboards and documentation. My major client was Los Angeles Metropolitan Transportation Authority where I created a dashboard for the public to see all aspects of projects. I also was instrumental in converting their project management software to Oracle Unifier and Oracle BI Suite.

Full-stack Ruby and Rails engineer on the e-commerce team. This is a full-stack role including jQuery, Grid, Bootstrap, etc. Duties included internal api development and maintenance, interfacing with external apis, maintaining a customer facing app as well as the administration side used by doctors and other office staff.

OWNER / LEAD DEVELOPER AT HIVEMIND ENGINEERING; SAN RAMON, CA- 2012-2016

Hivemind Engineering provided enterprise level development, monitoring, hosting and backups to small and medium e-commerce businesses. While our specialty was e-commerce, our services applied to a broad range of companies in this market.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT MALWAREBYTES; SAN JOSE, CA - APRIL 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

I started at Malwarebytes as a RoR developer strictly. I spent countless hours increasing test coverage from 24 to 95+ percent. I eventually took over Devops for my group and spent a lot of time in AWS. I also redesigned the event system to use Fluent brokers. This not only separated concerns but it also solved a major issue; every time Influxdb would go down it would take the app with it. I also contributed to the Influx-ruby gem as well as Influx.

ENGINEERING LEAD AT ONELOGIN; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JULY 2014 - FEBRUARY 2015

90% of my time was Ruby / Ruby on Rails development on the main backend authentication systems. I also began developing an OSX OpenDirectory setup that would allow multiple companies to simultaneously share a single directory (built in Linux) without colliding. I was successful in that project, however I left the company before it was ever integrated into the product. This was a difficult task requiring a lot of ingenuity as I could find no Internet postings where someone had successfully done so.

SENIOR RUBY SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT DEMANDBASE; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JUNE 2012 - JUNE 2014

At Demandbase, developers built and managed their own environments in AWS alongside their applications. I enjoyed this as I knew my application well, what it needed, and when to tweak it if needed. We ran both continuous integration and continuous deployment. The app would auto-deploy on regular intervals. I spent 99% of my time here in Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Grape, and Chef. The remaining time was the little bits I had to manage manually in AWS. I do have extensive Unix experience and mentored many during this time. I was also willing to build entire environments for others when time constraints were tough. I did spend my first 4 months at Demandbase working strictly with reporting and data warehousing using Fluent, S3, and Hadoop. I wrote many reports that used Ruby to call upon Pig (this is before JRuby support in Hadoop) to generate reports in the background that were then delivered to the user's email address. We used Resque to manage jobs, catch errors, and restart jobs when needed. This was a fantastic learning experience for me as I had never worked with a data warehouse that processed hundreds of millions of requests per day.

SR. ENGINEERING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT MEGAPATH; PLEASANTON, CA - MARCH 2008 - JUNE 2012

Building network management and provisioning software using Ruby and Rails. The main focus of this new project was Security as a Service and was the back-end that provisioned the company's core product handling thousands of requests per day. Responsibilities also included Linux systems administration, Mysql DBA, Netcool development and support. I also spent considerable time working on a small team tasked with obtaining then maintaining our PCI compliance.

VP SOFTWARE AND SYSTEMS ENGINEERING AT ASSETSHADOW; PLEASANTON, CA - JANUARY 2007 - MARCH 2008
I was responsible for building the entire company infrastructure from the ground up. This included the planning and implementation of all aspects of colocation facilities. I designed and implemented the network, server, and application service architectures. I lead the development team in maintaining the legacy application, written in Perl, while porting the software to Ruby and Rails.

SR. ENGINEERING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT MEGAPATH; PLEASANTON, CA - MAY 2001 - JANUARY 2007
Building network management and provisioning software using Perl, Mysql, and eventually Ruby and Rails. Responsibilities also included Linux systems administration, Mysql DBA, Netcool development and support. I was responsible for all systems administration for the engineering team including

managing all collocations that housed servers in the network.

UNIX SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR, MAIL & SECURITY AT NBCI; SAN FRANCISCO, CA - JANUARY 2001 - MARCH 2001 My team was responsible for all Unix security tasks across thousands of servers. I spent considerable time developing tools to automate deployments, manage ssh keys on thousands of servers, automate patching and upgrading of systems, and monitoring of systems and associated services.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT VIP SALES COMPANY; TULSA, OK - JANUARY 1998 - DECEMBER 2000

Informix 4GL programming, converted entire infrastructure from serial to ethernet. I also replaced all terminals with PC's and provided full support, hardware and software. I eventually wrote a lot of C++ and Powerbuilder code to convert the application to modern platforms.

Education

SPLUNK; SAN FRANCISCO, CA

Splunk Core Certified Consultant, 2020

MODESTO JUNIOR COLLEGE; MODESTO, CA

Business And Computer Science, (MIS) 2007 - 2009 Activities and Societies: Photography

TULSA COMMUNITY COLLEGE; TULSA, OK

Computer Science, 1998 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Free Math Tutoring

UNION HIGH SCHOOL; TULSA, OK

Computer Science, 1989 - 1993 Activities and Societies: DECA

Skills

Splunk, Python, Perl, MySQL, JavaScript, Unix, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Java, Android, Linux / Unix, Network Security, Network Engineering, Big Data, Hadoop, Pig, SaaS, REST, SOA Design, Sinatra, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Lean Software Development, Management, Cloud Computing, Juniper, Redback, Oracle, Linux System Administration, C#, Apache, Python, Enterprise Software, Microsoft SQL Server, Software Engineering, Agile Methodologies, Security, Bash, Web Applications, Databases, DNS, HTML, Distributed Systems, System Administration, TCP/IP, JSON, Objective-C, Git, Software Development, Web Development, Desktop Development, Mobile Development, Oracle Unifier, Oracle BI

References

Brian Criss; Executive VP; DR McNatty & Associates: 949.367.7990 x7995

Sean Crandall; VP Network Engineering; Amazon: 408.781.7979

Steve Guastella; VP Engineering; TNCI: 512.784.3230 Adrienne Dale; COO; adrienne.dale@pivotal-llc.com

Ron McClain; Sr Manager Devops; Sony Interactive (Playstation Network): 510.673.7621 (Many more

references available upon request.)